<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Black History: March On</title>
    <link>https://blackhistorymarchon.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Black History: March On</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blackhistorymarchon.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rediet Abebe</title>
      <link>https://blackhistorymarchon.com/timeline/rediet-abebe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blackhistorymarchon.com/timeline/rediet-abebe/</guid>
      <description>Rediet Abebe is an Ethiopian computer scientist working in algorithms and artificial intelligence. She is an Assistant Professor of Computer Science at the University of California, Berkeley and a Junior Fellow at the Harvard Society of Fellows.[1]
On Dr. Abebe&amp;rsquo;s website, she describes her research interests:
 My research broadly falls in the fields of algorithms and AI, with a focus on equity and justice concerns. My work has provided new mathematical and computational frameworks for problems related to poverty and inequality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://blackhistorymarchon.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:10:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blackhistorymarchon.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black History in March?</title>
      <link>https://blackhistorymarchon.com/timeline/black-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blackhistorymarchon.com/timeline/black-history/</guid>
      <description>Black history still matters after Black History Month in February. I encourage people to keep learning about the important contributions Black people have made to the world. Unfortunately for some, the focus on the past may lead to ignoring the present realities of systemic racism and social injustices.
As we acknowledge the past, we can also recognize Black history in the making. I want to dedicate this coming month to today&amp;rsquo;s Black pioneers who march on toward creating a brighter future for all people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
